## Rogério Moreira

Braga, Portugal r@rgllm.com • +351 918821769 • https://rgllm.com

#### ABOUT ME

I am a software engineer focused in front-end development, based in Braga, Portugal, who enjoys well-structured and clean code that is easy to read, test and maintain. I also particularly enjoy to lead teams tech-wise and to architect and design software solutions. I like sharing my experience with others and mentoring them to become better software developers.

These are the technologies I enjoy to work with: TypeScript, React, NextJS, React Native, Prisma ORM and Tailwind.

# PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS & ACTIVITIES

#### Trainline,

Software Engineer - Front-end (Contractor)

Full-stack development from front-end (React), API development (Express.js and GraphQL), server infrastructure (AWS, Docker, monitoring) to automated testing.

Things I worked on:

- Working on the convergence of high traffic EU and UK train journey web applications.
- Working on building the first version of Trainline's while-label solution.
- Improving Trainline's booking flow for EU markets.
- Working on Trainline's design system.

2020 - present

#### Mindera,

Software Engineer

Frontend Software Engineer, working with external clients. Apart from that, I am also involved in the recruitment process, conducting FE technical interviews and mentoring internships.

2020-present

#### Pixelmatters,

Front-End Developer

Working in the development of web applications and websites for US and UK based clients.

2018 - 2020

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Universidade do Minho, Braga, Portugal

M.S in Software Engineering

Sep 2017 – Nov 2019

- Intelligent Systems (Artificial Intelligence)
- Software Systems Engineering (Web Engineering and Software Design)
- B.S in Software Engineering

Sep 2014 – Jun 2017

### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

#### **Departamento de Informática**, Universidade do Minho

• M.S Student, Informatics Department

Feb 2018 – Jul 2018

- 4th year project: Search of correlation trajectories between functional MRI data
- Supervisors: Prof. Victor Alves (Algoritmi) and Dr. Nicolás Lori (ICVS)
- · Focus: machine Learning, data mining, data analysis

#### Master Thesis, Informatics Department

Sep 2018 – Dec 2019

- Building a research platform for brain connectivity data
- Supervisors: Prof. Victor Alves (Algoritmi) and Dr. Nicolás Lori (ICVS)
- Focus: bioinformatics, machine learning, data analysis

PUBLICATIONS Building an imagining-based research platform for the implementation of experiments with brain

connectivity data, See Publication

**LANGUAGES** • Portuguese: Native language.

• English: Fluent (speaking, reading, writing).

SKILLS • Languages: JavaScript/TypeScript

• Frameworks/Libraries: React, React Native, NextJS, GraphQL

■ **DevOps:** Docker, AWS

• **Testing:** Jest, React Testing Library

**PROJECTS** • Jornal O Minho : https://ominho.pt

OPEN SOURCE PROJECTS

• rgllm.com my personal website and blog which I built using NextJS

• **Awesome Portugal Data:** a repository of portuguese open data and open APIs

**SOCIAL** • **Github:** https://github.com/rgllm/

NETWORKS • LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rgllm